<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>My Data Journey on Chekwei&#39;s Portfolio</title>
    <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/</link>
    <description>Recent content in My Data Journey on Chekwei&#39;s Portfolio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A simple ML App dockerized and deployed on Google Cloud Platform</title>
      <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project5/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Aug 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project5/</guid>
      <description>Overview Project&amp;rsquo;s Objective Simple web app that predicts survivability during the Titanic Disaster. Powered by Streamlit. Dockerized and deployed on Google Cloud Platform.
  Simple ML web app, trained with Scikit-Learn and built via Streamlit
  Experiment with dockerization and further deploy on cloud platforms
  Model validation score is around 83% via Random Forest Classifier Dataset available via kaggle
  Dockerfile Dockerfile is like a list of steps/commands used to assemble a Docker image</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Car Resale Price Prediction App Deployed with Flask and Heroku</title>
      <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project4/</guid>
      <description>Overview Dataset from Cardekho, leading car sale platform in India, contains information about used cars, with features like km_driven, fuel type, transmission type, number of previous owners and present retail price.
Project&amp;rsquo;s Objective To predict the car resale price and to productionize the project to be used in real world.
Model RandomizedSearchCV performed with RandomForestRegressor to give best hyperparameters.
R2: 0.92
MSE: 1.84
Distribution plot
y_test against y_pred
 Scatter plot</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Curse of dimensionality: Feature Selection with Chi-Square Test, ANOVA Test and RFE</title>
      <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>Overview Dataset includes 20 features (RAM, Internal Memory, Phone Width, Phone Height, Phone Weight, With/Without Bluetooh, Camera Pixels etc). The goal is to find predict actual price range of each of the phones.
Project&amp;rsquo;s Objective To examine how different feature selection techniques will improve classification accuracy.
Model used throughout the project will be RandomForestClassier with default hyperparameters only.
Models  Baseline Model  Kitchen sink method, which included all features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving model performance on minority class with SMOTE and ADASYN</title>
      <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>Overview The dataset is related to red variant of the Portuguese &amp;ldquo;Vinho Verde&amp;rdquo; wine, which contains physicochemical of 1599 records of red wines. Initially, dataset included a dependent feature [quality], which is a score between 0 to 10. The higher the score, the better the wine. However, most of the scores are concentrated between 5 or 6.
Project has turned this into a classification problem, by setting an arbitrary cutoff for wine quality of 7 and higher classified as &amp;lsquo;good/1&amp;rsquo; and the remainder as &amp;lsquo;bad/0&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Iowa Housing Prediction using end-to-end ML Pipeline</title>
      <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jun 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Project Overview With 79 explanatory variables describing (almost) every aspect of residential homes in Ames, Iowa, this project aims to predict the final price of each home.
Objective Project aims to build an end-to-end ML pipeline that allows business to train and predict house prices in two ways as they wish
  as a regression problem
  as a classification problem (by binning the prices into 4 categorical quartiles)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://chekwei4.github.io/Chek_Wei_Portfolio/contact/</guid>
      <description>Let&amp;rsquo;s keep in touch.
   Platform URL     LinkedIn https://linkedin.com/in/chiachekwei   Github https://github.com/chekwei4   Medium https://chekweichia.medium.com   Email chekwei@me.com    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
